Guide to the Ayers family plantation history collection, circa 1850-2015 MS 635
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: People (photographs, genealogies and ephemera, boxes 38-39)
  - Photos of unidentified people: WWI soldiers at Fort Logan; WWII baby and housing; band competition; athletes (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - WWI panoramic, US Army soldiers, Baton Rouge (Oversize Panoramic box 1)
    - WWI panoramic "Antigone: The Ship That Brought Us Home, May 29, 1919" (Oversize Panoramic box 1)
  - Photos of unidentified laborers: Ayers Plantation laborers; prison laborers (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Photos of unidentified people (Box 39, Folder 22)
- Series III: Places (photographs, histories and ephemera, boxes 39-40)
  - Ames, Iowa (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Anna, Illinois: "Footprints of the Presbyterians, 1866-1966" (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Anna, Illinois: various places to be listed (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Carbondale, Illinois, 1919-1994 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Circleville, Ohio, 1973 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Jacksonville, Illinois: "The Ayers Family in Jacksonville" unpublished text by Laura McDonald, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Jacksonville, Illinois: Ayers family homes, Ayers Bank, Ayers donated hospital, Map of A.E. Ayers property (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Mississippi River Basin travels, Ayers women (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Oshkosh, Wisconsin, ca. 1915 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Shaw, Mississippi (Sunflower County): photographs, map, and brief history (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Union County, Illinois (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Vicksburg, Mississippi (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Washington D.C., 1949 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Winchester and Kankakee, Illinois (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - American West (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Fort Pike, Louisiana (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Travel, transportation images (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Manila, Philippines, 1912 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - France and Italy, WWI (Townsend Ayers) (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Earthquake, Arcadia, California, 1970 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - American Legion parade, San Antonio, TX, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Account of Elizabeth III's coronation, 1953, London, England (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Places, unidentified (Box 40, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Correspondence (boxes 40-42)
  - Ann Elizabeth Ayers (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Annie Reese Ayers (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Augustus Marshall Ayers (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Augustus Townsend Ayers (Box 40, Folder 21-22)
  - Augustus Townsend Ayers (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
  - Clara Elizabeth Ayers (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Edward Howe "Bud" Ayers (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Esther Mary Ayers (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
  - Harmon Allan Ayers (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Jane Allison Ayers (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Reese Ayers (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Betty-Jane "Betts" Bergeson (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Anna Magdalena Boettner (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Augusta Minna Boettner (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Fred Boettner (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - George H. Boettner (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Elizabeth Mary Boettner (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Mary Clara "Molly" Brown (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Ann Elizabeth Diller (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Florence Diller (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Elizabeth Fisher (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - King George V to the US Troops, April 1918 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Helen Krueger (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Esther Mary Martin (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Dr. Sidney Condon Martin (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Elizabeth Ayers McCarty (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Jane Brown McCarty (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - William B. McCarty, Jr. (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Roger Martin (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - John J. Pershing (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Rixleben family (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Grace "Gay" Ufford (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Minna F. Stone (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified authors (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Friends of Esther Mary Ayers (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Audio letter: to Ayers family in Anna, IL, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Audio letter: from Ayers family in Anna, IL to Blayney in NYC, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Audio letter: to Ayers family in Anna, IL (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Audio letter: to Ayers family in Anna, IL (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Audio letter: to Ayers family in Anna, IL (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Audio letter: to Augustus Ayers (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Audio letter: unlabeled (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Audio letter boxes with no tapes (Box 42, Folder 14)
- Series V: Education (box 42-43)
  - Esther Mary Martin, 1912 commencement announcement, Union Academy, Anna, Illinois (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Esther Martin, Sociology (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Esther Martin, Zoology, 190-1911 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Esther Martin, Physics (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Esther Martin, Astronomy, 1914 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Esther Martin, Herbarium and Plant Description, Anna., Ill., 1911 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Esther Martin, Psychology, 1914-1915 (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - Esther Martin, college work, ca. 1915 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Education articles (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Esther Mary Ayers' masters thesis, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, "Art in Southern Illinois" (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, "Art in Southern Illinois," drafts (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Alumni of Monticello Seminary School in Godfrey, Ill. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Illinois All-state High School Orchestra and Chorus, 1938 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - 1930's educational publications (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - 1950's educational publications (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, flower arrangement lecture notes, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, college life letters, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, Monticello College Alumni Directory, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, papers, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 13-14)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, personal notes and comments in continuing education for teachers, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, college life letters, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Closure of Monticello College in Godfrey, Illinois, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Ann Elizabeth Ayers high school graduation, Circleville, OH, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Publications on race, labor, current events (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Manuals, including grammar (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Anna-Jonesboro High School Class Reunions, 1988, 1998, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 21)
- Series VI: Property and estates (box 44)
  - Real property owned by the family in Illinois, Mississippi, and Louisiana (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Personal property (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Intellectual property (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Inter-family loans (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Samuel J. Martin estate, Union Co., Illinois, 1929 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Samuel Martin probate petition, 1898 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Berniece E. Rixelben estate (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Liquidated assets / finances documentation (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Esther May Ayers Martin estate (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Esther Mary Ayers estate (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Esther Mary Ayers, detailed listing of estate (Box 44, Folder 11-12)
- Series VII: Professional and business records (box 45-46)
  - Academia (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Banking careers (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Church / pastoral service of Augustus Marshall Ayers (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Civil service preference for Augustus Townsend Ayers (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - DuPont Research Labs, Sid Ayers (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Income taxes, 1915-1970s (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Insurance policy information, ca. 1920 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Medical doctor, Sidney C. Martin, late 1890s (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Medical doctor, Sidney C. Martin, writings on dysentery (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Medical doctor, Sidney C. Martin, handwritten medical case studies, ca. 1900 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Merchants patronized by Ayers family (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Merchant / business expenses, 1949 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Merchants - Bozeman General Store inventory (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Merchants - millwork in stores (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Real estate company, Ann Ayers Martin (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Rixleben Pharmacy calendar (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Salesman, Augustus Townsend Ayers, 1917-1931 records (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Salesman, Augustus Townsend Ayers (rope sales), 1940s-1960s (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Tailor, Frank C. Boettner (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Military service, 1919-1970s, correspondence and records (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Military service, Augustus Townsend Ayers, WWI, 1917-1919 (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - Plantation: Bozeman Plantation payroll, handwritten, July 1988 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Plantation: Bozeman and Lum Plantations, inventories, 1919 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Plantation: Illini Plantation, Sunflower County, Miss., real estate conveyances, 1916-1920 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Plantation: Illini Plantation, Sunflower County, Miss., inventory, price and terms for immediate walk out (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Jitney Jungle store layout (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Series X: Oral histories (box 46)
  - Interview of Esther Mary Ayers, transcript (audio not included in this collection) (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Interview of Betty Edwards, by Patricia Bell, 2015 (video and transcript) (Box 46, Folder 10)
- Series XI: Esther Mary Ayers travel photography and family snapshots (box 47-48 to be rehoused/arranged)
  - Photographic prints and slides (Box 47)
  - Photographic negatives (Box 48)
- Series VIII: Fine and performing arts (boxes 49-51)
  - Art / material culture interests of Esther Mary Ayers, including Kirkpatrick Pottery in Anna, Illinois (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Program for photography of Augustus Townsend Ayers at Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Performing arts: bagpipes and ballet (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Visual art: Sidney Ayers' matchbook cover scrapbook, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Visual art: postcards featuring landscape paintings, associated with Amy R. Kirkpatrick (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Visual art: images of sculpture by Harmon Ayers, paper arts such as handmade placecards and notecards, embroidered hankerchief "B" or "R" (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Visual art: Artists in Southern Illinois (newsclipping and book) (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Visual art: Documentation of distribution of Ayers estate arts and crafts, 2004 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Theater arts: scripts, newsclippings, playbills related to Ayers family (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Black and white photography by Augustus Townsend Ayers, Sidney Ayers, and Esther Mary Ayers (4x5 and 8x10 prints) (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Art photography prints (Box 50)
  - Art photography prints by Esther Mary Ayers (portraits and landscapes) (Box 51)
- Series IX: Books, Realia and oversize (boxes 52-55)
  - Dorin soap leaves (Box 52)
  - Small pins and buttons (Box 52)
  - French-English Littre-Webster dictionary owned by A. T. Ayers. Captain Infantry U.S.R. (Box 52)
  - Blue leather "Northwestern 15" keepsake, for an alum of Northwestern University 1915 (Box 52)
  - Lace pillow, doll size (Box 52)
  - Buxton leather wallet used by A.T. Ayers when he worked as a salesman for Broderick and Bascom Rope Co. (Box 52)
  - Leather wallet used by A.T. Ayers in late 1920s (Box 52)
  - German Iron Cross medal, WWI, on black and white ribbon (Box 52)
  - German "Gott Mit Uns" belt buckle (Box 52)
  - Metal container for a glass vial of ink (empty) (Box 52)
  - Metal perpetual calendar (Box 52)
  - "The Forty and Eight" American Legion Cap, MIssissippi, wool and leather (Box 52)
  - German book of mapping with bullet holes through it, found during the Great War (Box 52)
  - Oversize photographs from Series I: People (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Quilt (Box 53, Folder -)
  - Ayers family books regarding Illinois history, Southern Illinois State Normal School yearbooks, religion, and children's literature (Box 54)
  - Wooden toolbox, with tools (Box 55)
- Series X: Scrapbooks
  - Monticello Seminary class of 1915 senior year scrapbook of clippings, photographs, and ephemera (Box 56)
  - Esther Martin, high school graduation, Union Academy, Anna, Illinois, 1912 (Box 57)
  - Travel scrapbook, Esther Mary Ayers: Western Vacation (Illinois to Utah) 1948 (Box 57)
  - Travel scrapbook, Esther Mary Ayers: Trip to Sweden, Finland, and England, 1983 (Box 57)
  - Art photographs, unidentified and undated (Box 58)
  - Ayers family scrapbook, ca 1912-1918, Anna, Illinois (Box 58)
  - Esther Mary Ayers scrapbook, 1912 (Box 58)
  - Townsend Ayers scrapbook of football and friends, ca. 1911 (Box 58)
  - Esther Mary scrapbook of inspirational friendship quotes (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of Sigma Sigma Sigma convention at Pikes Peak, Colorado, with Alpha Nu delegates including Esther Mary Ayers, 1939 (Box 59)
- Series XI: Addendum of correspondence, photos, and documents, 1875-2005
  - Subseries A: Esther Mary Ayers correspondence, 1940-2002
    - 2002 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - 2001 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - 2000 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - 1999 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - 1998 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - 1997 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - 1996 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - 1995 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - 1994 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - 1993 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - 1990-1992 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - 1970-1973 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - 1966-1969 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - 1949 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - 1940-1948 (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Date unknown (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - Subseries B: Documents, 1878-1958
    - Settlement of estate of Mary Brown Ayers, Augustus T. Ayers executor, 1945 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Mr. and Mrs. A. T. Ayers correspondence, 1921-1958 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Business correspondence of Augustus T. Ayers, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Dr. and Mrs. S. C. Martin correspondence, 1900-1946 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Autograph books and travel diaries (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Social activities (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Church activities (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Records of household expenses, 1928-1940 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Documents relating to family deaths, 1928-1951 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - School records, 1878-1938 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Publications regarding Anna, Illinois, 1978-2004 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Recipes (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Military papers, 1892-1942 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Esther Mary Ayers' Class of 1938 reunion, 2001 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Writing fragments (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Subseries C: Photographs, 1875-2005
    - Industrial subjects, including cotton farming, transportation of cotton, cranes and cables, and African American laborers, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
    - Places, including travel snapshots of Colorado, Pennsylvania, Missouri, landscapes, domestic interiors, and many unidentified, 1930-2000 (Box 62, Folder 4-6)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 2000s (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1990s (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1980s (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1970s (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1960s (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1950s (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1940s (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1930s (Box 62, Folder 14-15)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1920s (Box 62, Folder 16-17)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), 1910s (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - People (Ayers family and friends), circa 1910 and earlier (Box 62, Folder 19)